在很長一段時間里 大家都知道
For as long as can be remembered, storks delivered babies
寶寶都是送子鳥送來的
from their perch on Stork Mountain.
這曾經是一種榮耀的象征
It was an honor and a privilege to serve.
這是我們的職責 我們核心的信仰
It was our duty, our core belief,
是我們血液中流淌的血脈
the driving force of our very lifeblood.
并不是總是一帆風順的
It wasn't always easy.
這是我們的挑戰
This was our challenge.
這是我們神圣的職責
This was our sacred duty.
無論多么的艱難或不可能
No matter how tough or impossible
或殘酷 嚴厲 不人道和野蠻
or brutal or harsh or inhumane or savage,
我們都將戰勝逆境
we would triumph over adversity.
抓到你了！
Gotcha!
- 在你的右邊   - 左邊
- On your right.  - Left.
自行車車道
Bike lane.
謝天謝地 我們不用再也做那個了
Thank goodness we don't do that anymore.
那里！ 就在那里！
There! Right there!
問題是
The problem was,
我們在遞送不同的東西
we had the wrong cargo.
我們的新手機！
Our new phones!
幸運的是 現在 送子鳥們在給角落商店公司送包裹
Luckily, now, storks deliver packages for Cornerstore. com!
我的伙計
My dude!
凱文! 看起來不錯啊 朋友！
Yo, Kevron! Lookin' good, my man!
天啊  我超喜歡這家伙！
Oh, I love this guy!
完美著陸 進行檢查
Perfect landing. Chiggy-check.
你是那個人！
You're the man!
什么？ 第一百萬份包裹？ 不可能
What? Millionth package? Not possible.
我想我才20歲
I thought I was only at 20.
朱尼爾 你要去慶祝一下嗎？
Hey, Junior, are you gonna celebrate?
你知道什么？ 你是對的 我的確要慶祝一下
You know what? You're right. I should celebrate.
你們這個周末都要什么？
What are you guys doing this weekend?
你們有空嗎？
Are you guys free?
我和我的妻子都在慶祝另一個紀念日
The wife and I are celebrating another anniversary.
給我的孩子取名
Got my kid's game this weekend.
家庭團聚 我們全家都會來
Family reunion. The whole family's coming.
噢 我只是想確認一下
Oh. Just wanted to confirm.
那么你們都很忙啊
That you were all busy.
我以為你們都很忙 還有你也是
I assumed you were all busy and you are.
那么 如果有要改變主意的 請讓我知道
So, if anything changes, let me know.
我可能要出門工作
I maybe could get out of work.
可能不可以 但是如果你可以的話請讓我知道
Probably can't, but let me know if you can.
那里的工作真不錯  大兄弟
Great job out there, brah!
謝謝  馬屁鴿
Thanks, Pigeon Toady.
看看我的女朋友
Check out my girlfriend.
- 她在加拿大  - 是啊 呵呵
- She's in Canada.  - Yeah-huh.
她移民了
She migrated.
- 她可不是編的  - 好吧
- She's not made up.  Okay.
快看她！ 快看她！
Look at her! Look at her!
- 她是真實的  - 太好了！
- She exists, brah! - That's great.
你們聽說過羅杰嗎？
Hey, did you guys hear about Roger?
天吶 你還好嗎？
Oh, my goodness. Are you okay?
什么？  我說...什么？ 好吧
What? Hey, brah. I say... What? Okay.
我可以和你說說我的女朋友嗎？
I tell you about my girlfriend?
老板想要見你
Hey, boss wants to see you.
亨特想要見我？
Hunter wants to see me?
好了 認真點 朱尼爾
All right. Head in the game, Junior.
所以 你是亨特 你在這里做什么？
So, you're Hunter. What do you do around here?
不 我討厭那樣
No, I hate that.
亨特 很高興 見到 你
Hunter. Nice. To. Meet. You.
不 那太呆了
No, that's too robot.
正常說話 正常說話 讓我們開始吧
Just say it normal. Just say it normal. Here we go.
很高興見到你！
Nice to meet you!
我是怎么了？
What is wrong with me?
朱尼爾
Junior.
亨特
Hunter.
你知道為什么我完全用玻璃打造我的辦公室
You know why I built my office entirely out of glass
即使鳥兒是看不到玻璃嗎？
even though birds can't see glass?
我不知道
I do not.
那我告訴你吧
Power move.
18年以前 為了拯救所以送子鳥 我宣布了
Eighteen years ago, I saved all storks by getting out of babies
取消了遞送寶寶的業務
and into package delivery.
現在 這個星期一，在大會上
Now, this Monday at Storkcon,
董事會宣布把我升職
the board will announce they're kicking me upstairs.
我將要準備任命做主席
I'm going to be named Chairman.
而這就意味你將被任命
Which means you are going to be named
老板
boss.
老板！
Boss!
酷 酷 酷！ 非常酷 非常酷
Cool, cool, cool. Very cool, very cool.
現在 睜大眼睛看看你的周圍
Now, look upon your domain with your eyes wide open.
很大
Wider.
我太喜歡了 這感覺很棒
I love it. Feels good.
如果你不能看見它 你是怎么當上老板的
How can you be boss if you can't look at it?
如果我瞎了 這就不值得了
If I go blind, it was worth it.
你知道作為一個老板最艱難的事是什么嗎？
You know the hardest thing about bein' boss?
凝望太陽？
Staring at the sun?
不 這很簡單
No, this is easy.
是否做一個像朋友的老板 或冷漠的老板 再或是古怪的老板
Whether to be like a friend boss or a distant, weird boss?
總是板著一副冷漠古怪的臉 你怎么了？
Always be distant and weird. What's the matter with you?
對不起
Sorry.
不 是 處理她
No, it's dealing with that.
那個孤兒小郁？
The orphan Tulip?
我不明白
I don't understand.
你知道為什么我們要停止遞送嬰兒嗎？
Do you know why we stopped delivering babies?
因為有很多其他得到寶寶的方式？
Because there are so many other ways of getting babies?
是的 但這不是全部
Yes. But that's not the whole story.
18年前 當我們仍在遞送人類嬰兒時
Eighteen years ago, when we still delivered human infants,
一個名叫賈斯伯的送子鳥發瘋地嘗試養一個嬰兒
a stork named Jasper went crazy and tried to keep a baby.
小郁的定位器破裂了
Tulip's beacon broke.
她的地址被摧毀了 所以我們無法再遞送她
Her address was destroyed, so we could no longer deliver her.
我的寶貝！
My baby!
這就是之后我意識到遞送寶寶是沒有前途的
It was then I realized that there was no future in baby delivery.
現在 那個孤兒小郁剛到18歲 這意味我們可以解放她了
Now, the orphan Tulip has just turned 18, which means we can finally liberate her
讓她回到人類生活的世界
and return her to the human world.
但是她并不是個麻煩
But she's no trouble.
她不是
Oh, she isn't, is she?
這是我們的利潤表
Here's our profit chart.
- 我喜歡有一個很好的利潤表  - 我也是
- I love a good profit chart.  - Me, too.
耶！
Yeah!
小郁在山上度假時睡著后得流感了
The peaks are when Tulip is on vacation, asleep or out with the flu.
那些山谷就是她試圖去幫助的對象
The valleys are when she tries to help.
我會讓她走的
Cool. I will liberate her. Consider her liberated.
如果她不想走呢
And if she doesn't want to be liberated?
解雇她 我是在說解雇她
Fire her. I'm talking about firing her.
真的？
Really?
你唯一需要去做的事是 等著在星期一升職為老板
The only thing you need to do to be named boss on Monday
但在此之前你要讓小郁走人
is liberate the orphan Tulip.
我可能沒有講清楚 我的意思是開除她！
If I'm not being clear, I mean fire her!
是 我現在就去做
Yes, sir. I am on it.
我查過有關你的所有信息
I have read between the lines and heard you overtly.
打擾一下！ 孤兒小郁？
Excuse me! Orphan Tulip?
朱尼爾？
Junior?
你在和我說話？
You're talkin' to me?
是的 孤兒小郁！
Yes, Orphan Tulip!
不 你不是從來都不和我說話的嗎
No, it's just that you never talk to me.
從今天不是了 孤兒小郁
Well, yeah, that's changing starting today, Orphan Tulip.
“小郁”就好了 “孤兒”太傷我心了
Oh, "Tulip" is just fine. "Orphan" hurts my heart.
我有好多問題要問你！
I have so many questions to ask you!
為什么你不下來和我一起聊聊？
Why don't you come down and we can talk all day?
好吧 我會下來的
Okay. I will be down.
和我的朋友一起
As will my friends.
我們準備飛下來
We are going to fly right down.
什么？不 不
What? No, no.
那是一只鵪鶉 一只鴯鹋 還有一只雞
That's a quail, an emu, there's a chicken.
它們都不會飛
They cannot fly.
但是 直到現在會飛了
Yeah. Until now.
她幫我們實現了夢想
She's helping us achieve our dreams.
- 對啊 道蘭  - 你知道的
- That's right, Dougland. - You know it.
如果你用那個桶的話那我沒話說
It is still a personal victory if you use the bucket.
那我們就不應那個
Okay, we'll all not use the bucket!
等一下 什么？
Wait, what?
哈哈！ 小郁還不適應
Ha-ha! Tulip doesn't fit in.
我們都是一樣的 唯有她是個怪人
We're all the same and she's a weirdo.
感覺不太好 她...
Whoa, whoa, whoa, that's not nice. She's...
她有著一個艱難的人生
She's had a hard life.
好吧
Okay.
這將是個偉大的時刻 伙計們！
This is gonna be great, guys!
倒計時
Countdown.
Three, two, one!
成功了！ 我們都在飛！
It's working! We're flying!
真棒
Yeah, yeah!
是啊
Yeah!
還不夠快 我還要更快！
Enough of this, I wanna go fast!
不！道蘭 等一下！
No! Dougland, wait!
不 不 不！
No, no, no!
這是我有生以來最偉大的日子
This is the greatest day of my life!
我在飛！
I'm flying!
這是屬于我的時刻！
This is my moment!
- 道蘭！ 不！   -別擋我的路！
- Dougland! No!  - Get out of my way!
壞道蘭！ 不！
Bad Dougland! No!
怎么可能我的夢想發展到如此可怕的地步？
How could my dreams go so horribly wrong?
抓住你們了！
I got ya!
好
Okay.
我在往下掉
I'm fallin'.
不！
Oh, no! No! No, no, no, no, no!
天吶
Oh, boy.
還不差
Oh. Oh, that's not so bad.
我著火了！
I got it. I got it. I got it! I got it!
I got it!
我很抱歉！  我真的 真的很抱歉
I'm sorry! Oh, I'm so, so sorry. Oh!
我不適合在任何我想去做的事情上
I don't fit in anywhere and all I want to do is help!
天吶
Oh, boy.
在你來
Before you finish,
祝我生日快樂之前
for you to come to wish me a happy birthday,
那是最棒的 你知道嗎？ 就像個小彩虹
that's just the nicest, you know? It's like a little rainbow.
謝謝
So, thank you.
那真的很棒
That's really nice.
但是 噢 抱歉 我打斷了你
But, oh, I'm sorry. I interrupted you.
你想要說什么？
What were you gonna tell me?
好吧
Oh, boy.
我有個絕妙的消息告訴你
I have wonderful news for you.
你被釋放了
You have been liberated.
什么意思？
What does that mean?
意思就是你被開除了
Well, it means that you are
fired.
- 什么？  - 你...
- What?  - You're...
你還好嗎？
Are you okay?
對不起 你...
Excuse me. You're...
你棒極了！
You're fantastic!
真的？
Really?
因為我剛剛炸毀了工廠
Because I just blew up most of the factory.
是的
Oh, yeah.
這太扭曲了！
What a twist! Um...
這意味...
Well, it means...
我要把你安排到其他適合你的崗位去
I'm putting you in charge of your very own department.
你是信件收發室的這個崗位的老大了
You are the new head of Letter Sorting.
我甚至還不知道我們還有信
I didn't even know we still got letters.
我們會有的！
We do!
- 現在 你要好好管理它們  - 當然！ 我會做得為之一驚的！
- And now, you're in charge of them. - Oh, yes! I will rock this!
你可以做得好的！
You will rock this!
- 耶！ 努力做好它！  - 去努力做好它吧！
- Oh, yeah! Rock it hard! - Gonna rock it hard!
這里的第一條規定是什么？
And what's the number-one rule?
用生命遞送！
Always deliver!
- 不對   是絕不能離開這間房間  - 噢
- Wrong. Never leave this room.
- Oh.
我一直以為這更多像是“力量”！
I always thought it was
something more like "Strength"!
- “決心” - 不 開玩笑的
- "Determination"! - Nope. That's way off.
第一條規定是 絕不能離開這里
Number-one rule, never leave this room.
好吧 如果...
Okay, well, if that...
無聊 無聊 無聊
Bored, bored, bored.
你是怎么上下班呢？
So, how was your commute?
我是搭載具的
Oh, I took the bucket.
我也是 真的有準備的喔
Me, too. Real backed up.
那是
Oh, yeah.
你有聽說過史蒂夫和格洛麗亞嗎？
You hear about Steve and Gloria?
什么？
What?
我聽說她們是個項目
I hear they're an item.
- 不  - 是的
- No.  - Yeah.
你在開玩笑嗎？
Are you kidding me?
你們是在討論我嗎？
Are you guys talking about us?
你們最好別討論我們
You guys better not be talking about us.
我很自信地告訴你
I told you that in confidence.
你不會使得她傷心的 她是我的生命！
You don't make her upset. She's my life!
噢 不 我把它大聲地說出來了
Oh, no, I said it out loud.
你不應該去說任何事！
You're not supposed to say anything!
對不起 伙計們 露出馬腳咯！
Sorry, guys. Cat's out of the bag!
- 不！  - 呼~
- No!  - Meow!
是你在說閑話嗎？ 不準再說閑話了！ 去人力資源部！
Are you gossiping? No gossip allowed! Go to HR!
我之前提醒過你們兩個 因為我聽說你們有些問題
I've called you both in because hear you've been having problems.
- 重要的是我們有...  - 先從她開始！
- And it's important we have... - She's the one who started it!
- 你好大的膽！  - 你好大的膽！
- How dare you!  - How dare you!
- 你們都挺大膽的！ 你們都被開除了！  - 你不能開除我！
- How dare both of you! You're fired! - You can't fire me!
- 我就要這么做！  - 等一下！ 我很抱歉 我不是這個意思！
- I just did!   - Wait! I'm so sorry, I didn't mean that!
- 伙計們！ 來集體擁抱一個！  - 集體擁抱！
- Guys! Group hug!  - Group hug!
我在擁抱著自己 好吧
I'm hugging myself. Okay.
誰給我寫封信啊！
Somebody write me a letter!
進來吧 忍者指揮官
Come in, Ninja Commander.
這里是牛仔宇航員特工內特 請回復
This is Cowboy Astronaut Agent Nate, over.
忍者團指揮官 你還在嗎？
Ninja Team Commander, are you in position?
我準備發起突擊了
I'm about to launch the assault.
我們絕對可以做到的
We can absolutely do that.
絕對沒有問題
That's not gonna be a problem.
哈哈！ 冰凍博士！
Ha-ha! Dr. LeFreeze!
你可能以為會讓我以一敵七千 但是你千算萬算還是沒有算到一件事
You may have me outnumbered 7,000 to one, but you weren't counting on one thing,
我不是一個人
I'm not alone.
忍者部隊 進攻！
Ninja force, attack!
忍者部隊？
Ninja force?
不！
Oh, ow! No! Oh!
這就是我的盡頭了
This is the end.
忍者部隊 告訴我的妻子我依然愛著她
Ninja force, tell my wife I loved her.
加德納房地產 海倫...
Gardner Real Estate. Henry...
- 還有莎拉  - ...加德納！
- And Sarah...   - ...Gardner!
沒有了加德納 一幢房子就不再是個家了！
A house is not a home without a Gardner!
忍者指揮官 你在哪？
Ninja Commander, where were you?
- 你可以等一下嗎？  - 你可以...
- Uh, can you hold one second?  - Can you just...
你答應過我今天下午去打敗冰凍博士的
You promised me that we were taking down Dr. LeFreeze this afternoon.
你沒有出現
You didn't show up,
然而現在他控制了西歐的大部分地區
and now he controls most of Western Europe.
民族壓力在上升
Ethnic tension is on the rise.
是啊
Yeah.
- 我們在打完電話之后就結束了 好嗎？  - 真的？
- We're totally done after this call, okay?  - Really?
- 再給多5分鐘  - 然后我們就停止
- Five more minutes.  - And then we'll stop.
我們保證
We promise.
我們絕不停息 那就是加德納的承諾
We never stop. That's the Gardner promise.
即使是5分鐘
Not even for five minutes.
快看！ 那有一個我們的長凳廣告
Oh, look! There's one of our bench ads.
你知道它上面說了些什么嗎？
And you know what it says?
“我們永不停息”
"We never stop."
我們永不停息
We never stop. We never stop.
那有一個停車標志 我們正在停止
There's a stop sign. We're stopping.
只是等一下下而已
We do stop for that.
我愛你 兄弟
I love you, brother.
我們就像是最好的朋友一樣生活在一起！
It's like we're best friends that live together!
我們要賺錢
And we yield.
有錢了就可以得到這幢房子 凱爾
And the yield you're gonna get on this house, Kyle...
正如我們所說的 你要長大...
And that's what we were saying, like you've gotta be up...
媽媽 爸爸 我已經決定我想要一個小弟弟了
Mom, Dad, I've decided I want a baby brother.
親愛的 你可以...  - 你可以等一下嗎？
- Oh, honey, can you...  - Can you hold one second?
我覺得一家三口挺不錯的
I think we're fine as a family of three.
為什么我不能有一個小弟弟？
Why can't I have one?
簡單點來說吧 你們從哪里得到我的？
Let's make this easy.  Where do you get one?
為什么你們一直在笑又不回答我的問題？
Why are you laughing and not answering me?
你們是從哪兒得到我的？
Where did you get me?
你們在笑什么？
What is the joke?
這是一個完全不同于我們現在正在進行的項目
Is there a different subject?
好吧 這輛車上現在有著超級怪異的氣氛
Okay, so there's a super weird vibe in this car right now.
寶貝 這太甜蜜了
Oh, honey, this is very sweet.
但是我們有了你
But we have you.
就是我們的所有
And that's all we need.
對
That's right.
不 不 不   別感到不開心
No, no, no, don't feel bad.
你可以隨時打電話我們
You can call us anytime.
無論是早上 中午或者夜晚
Call us morning, noon or night.
周末 假期
Weekends, holidays.
不 我們會在圣誕節拿起手機
No, we will pick up the phone on Christmas.
好吧 我不... 我們能嗎？
Oh, well, I don't... Will we?
是的 你可以在圣誕節那天呼叫我
Yeah, you can call us on Christmas.
“親愛的送子鳥”
"Dear Stork Delivery Service,
“我們的名字叫海倫和莎拉”
"our adult names are Henry and Sarah.
“我們是一對成年父母 有一個絕對完美的兒子叫做內特”
"We are adult parents of an absolutely perfect son named Nate.
“他真的想要一個小弟弟”
"He really deserves a baby brother.
“作為成年人 這是我們成人的信仰”
"As adults, it is our adult belief
“如果這個寶寶沒有忍者技能 那就太不負責了”
"that it would be irresponsible
if this baby did not have ninja skills.
“真摯的 已經成年的父母海倫?加德納和莎拉?加德納敬上”
"Sincerely, adult parents Henry and Sarah Gardner comma adults.
“而不是內特”
"Not Nate.
“注明：他必須得有忍者技能！”
"P.S. He has to have ninja skills!"
耶
Hi-ya!
完成！
Nailed it.
生日快樂 親愛的小郁！ 祝你生日快樂！
Happy birthday, dear Tulip! Happy birthday to you!
伙計們 太感謝你們了！ 噢 我的天
Guys, thank you so much! Oh, my gosh.
你不覺得朱尼爾把你安置在這是為了把你逼上絕路嗎？
Don't you think Junior put you down here to get you out of the way?
謝莉爾 那太不公平了 你為什么那么說？
Cheryl, that's not fair. Why would you say that?
什么？ 我忍不住就這么說了 因為我是你直言不違的朋友啊
What? I can't help it. I'm your outspoken friend.
我從來沒那么做過
I've never done this before,
但是我勸你快離開這里
but I'm gonna have to ask you to leave.
啊哈！ 一封信！
Aha! A letter!
“H.I.部門”
"The H.I. Department."
沒聽說過啊
Don't know that one.
他說這里等我第一條規定是“不能離開這里”
He said the number-one rule is "Don't leave."
但是如果我不去送信 我將一事無成
But if I don't deliver the letter, I won't be doing my job.
我會幫你掩護的
I'll cover for you!
好 謝謝！
Okay, thanks!
我有一個令人振奮的消息
I have excellent news.
我曾經關注過小郁的問題
I have taken care of the Tulip problem.
棒極了
Wonderful.
星期一 這將全都是你的了
Monday, it'll all be yours.
除非有一大堆亂七八糟的事情
Barring any monumental screw-up.
你知道當你是個老板的時候我們要做什么嗎？
Do you know what we'll do when you're boss?
不知道 告訴我！
No. Tell me!
我們一起燒烤
We'll barbecue together.
一起畫畫
We'll point at things together.
一起建立團隊
We'll team-build together.
一起穿衣服
We'll wear suits together.
你絕不會覺得孤獨 因為角落商店就是你的家
You'll never be alone because Cornerstore is your family.
- 什么？  -我會像你爸一樣
- What? - And I'll be like your dad.
然后你就像我的兒子一樣
And you're like my son.
我的兒子
My son-ployee.
就像一家人一樣...
And like any family...
不 不 不 不 不
No, no, no, no, no.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
怎么把這東西給關掉？
How do you turn this thing off?
打短柄墻球還有釣魚
...and racquetball and fishing...
為什么會有這么多屏幕？
Why are there so many screens?
關掉 關掉 關掉！
Turn off, turn off, turn off!
你將得到一切你想要的
You're about to get everything you ever wanted.
好想法 亨特！
Great convo, Hunter!
我太蠢了！
I'm so stupid!
我就應該開除她！為什么我當時不開除她？
I should have just fired her! Why didn't I just fire her?
小郁！
Tulip!
嘿！
Hey!
你在房間外面干什么？
Hey, what are you doing out of the room?
我不是告訴過你不準離開那間房間嗎！
I told you not to leave the room!
此言差矣 我在幫助我自己打掩護
Nah, it's cool. I'm covering for myself.
什么？
What?
好吧 我們得離開這里了
Okay, we need to get outta here.
快點 我們現在必須得走了
Come on. We have to go now.
朱尼爾 你告訴過我去做好這件事 我不會令你失望的！
Junior, you asked me to do a thing,
and I will not fail you!
用生命遞送！
Always deliver!
等一下！ 不！
Wait! No!
這是嬰兒工廠！
This is the Baby Factory!
這是嬰兒工廠？
This is the Baby Factory?
不 不 不！
No, no, no!
看呀！
See ya!
為什么你要這么做？
Why did you do that?
觸地得分 小郁！
Touchdown Tulip!
別在那慶祝了！
Stop celebrating!
我想這應該到那邊去的
I think it was supposed to go over there.
你是對的 那是個錯誤
You're right. That was wrong.
不要啊！
Oh, come on!
為什么我們不在幾年前摧毀它？
Why didn't we destroy this place years ago?
我的天！
Oh, my gosh!
我不敢相信我都看到了什么！
I can't believe what I'm seeing!
你看到所有的一切了嗎？
Do you see all this?
朱尼爾！ 那太驚奇了！
Junior! This is amazing!
為什么把按鈕安置在那？
Why put the button there? Uh...
來吧！
Come on!
這是停了嗎？
Is it off?
我想是的
Uh, I believe so.
你還好嗎？
Are you okay?
你的翅膀看起來有點錯位
Your wing looks a little mangled.
我的翅膀很好 一點事都沒有
My wing is fine. It's A-O-great.
是嗎 但是看起來好像挺糟糕的
Yeah, that seems bad.
走吧
Let's go.
此地不宜久留
This place is dangerous.
那是什么？
Huh. What is that?
我去 一個人？
Cool beans.
- 什么？  - 什么？
- What? - What?
- 發生什么事了？  - 媽媽 爸爸
- What's happening? - Mom, Dad.
送子鳥正在給我帶來一個弟弟！
The storks are bringing me a baby brother!
這聽起來像是個美好的夢 伙計
That sounds like a nice dream, buddy.
快回去睡覺吧 親愛的
Let's go back to sleep, honey.
這是我有生以來最棒的一天了！
This is the best day of my life!
這是我有生以來最糟糕的一天了！
This is the worst day of my life!
亨特會殺了我的！
Hunter's gonna kill me!
- 為什么我們不告訴任何一個人？  -你瘋了嗎？
- Why don't we just tell someone?  - Are you insane?
如果有人發現這里 我就死定了
If anyone finds out about this,
I am dead meat.
我的老板夢也就破裂了
My hopes of becoming boss destroyed.
不 不 不
No, no, no.
來吧！
Come on!
怎么了？
What up?
- 你好  馬屁鴿  - 你好
- Hey, Pigeon Toady. - Hey, there.
很酷的金屬物 老兄
Hey, cool metal thing, brah.
新品種包裹？里面是什么？
New kind of package? What's in it?
- 糖果盒 - 有一些氣體
- Candy canes. - Some gas.
酷斃了 老兄 你昨晚看比賽了？
Cool, brah. You catch the game last night?
- 噢 是啊 真的是場壯觀的比賽  - 棒極了的比賽
- Oh, yeah. Real great game. - Excellent playing.
是啊 前四分之一賽程真的太糟糕了
Yeah, too bad about the last quarter.
- 是啊 那實在太糟糕了  - 真的太失敗了
- Yeah, that was too bad. - Real bummer.
然而還有一點點時間剩余 我們把它拉出來...
And yet then with a little time left, we pulled it out...
- 是啊！  - 耶！
- Totally! - Yeah.
只是在最后一秒再次失球
...only to lose it again in the last second.
- 這太令人失望了  - 這真是失落啊
- Such a disappointment. - It was a comedown.
- 只不過球又回來了 - 真是我生命中最棒的一天！
- Only to get it back. - Best day of my life!
- 然后又丟球了 ！  - 真是我生命中最糟糕的一天！
- Only to lose it! - Worst day of my life!
然后球又回來了
Only to get it back.
看來這是一個過山車比賽！
A roller-coaster of a game!
然后又再次失球了
Only to lose it again.
多么贊的比賽啊！ 我們走了  再見
What a game! Here we go, see you later.
再見！
Bye!
沒什么大不了的
Cool. No big deal.
等...等一下
Wait... Wait a second.
昨晚沒有比賽
There was no game last night.
什么...
What the...
來 去我的工作室
Come on. Let's get to my workshop.
我們在那兒會安全的
We'll be safe there.
好吧 好了 好了 好了
All right, okay, all right, all right.
這一切都不會有問題的
It's gonna be okay. It's gonna be okay.
我們要低調  好嗎？
We just need to keep a low-pro here. Okay?
如果有人看到一個帶著孩子的送子鳥
If one person sees a stork with a baby,
我被任命做老板的機會就毀了 所以...
my chances of being named boss are ruined. So...
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
- 我想看看那個孩子！  - 不 不 不
- I wanna see the baby! - No, no, no.
我們不能打開那個東西
We do not open that thing.
只是一個露面就可以可愛到你生活不能自理
Just a brief exposure to baby cuteness can ruin your life.
還記得賈斯伯嗎？
Remember Jasper?
我正在試著把我的手指放上去那 我想不起來誰...
Hmm. I'm trying to put my finger on it. I can't think of who...
你正在遭受諷刺因為他改變了你的人生歷程
You're being sarcastic because he changed the course of your life.
- 是啊  - 對啊
- That's right. - Yeah.
嗯 這個怎么樣？
Huh. How about this?
嗯 好吧 送子鳥大會是在下個星期一 今天是星期五
Huh. All right, Storkcon is on Monday. Today is Friday.
如果我們把這個孩子送到她家 我仍能做上老板
If I can just deliver this thing by then, I can still be named boss.
加德納家 我來啦！
Gardner family, here I come!
但是你的翅膀折斷了 你不能...
But your wing's broken. You can't...
設定一個計劃！ 死守計劃！
Make a plan! Stick to the plan!
用生命遞送！
Always deliver!
我不能再飛了！
I'll never fly again!
那是什么？
What's that?
你說的什么是什么？
Hmm? What's what?
那個 就在那
That. Right there.
那個？ 不可以
Uh... Oh, that? No.
那沒什么
That's nothing.
看起來像架飛機
Looks like an airplane.
好吧 我猜應該是和飛機一類的
Well, it kind of is an airplane, I guess.
太好了 我來駕駛它
Great! I'll use it.
好吧 這要花費我很長時間去弄它
Oh, well, it kind of took me a long time to make,
像要幾年時間...
like years and years...
好了 見證奇跡的時刻到了
Great. All leading to this moment.
我修復它是為了其他事情
I'm saving it for something else.
- 為了什么？
- For what?
你打算用它做什么？
What were you gonna use it for?
為角落商店公司遞送包裹是我的夢想
Uh, it's my dream to deliver packages for Cornerstore.com.
好了 那個 孩子
Oh, well, hey there, kid.
現在是你的機會了
Now's your chance.
- 呃 我不知道  - 好吧
- Uh, I don't know.  - Yeah.
我甚至不知道他是否能飛
I don't even know if it flies.
你知道嗎？
You know what?
你可以使用它了 讓我們一起遞送嬰兒吧
Yeah, you can use it. Let's deliver this baby.
你確定嗎？
Are you sure though?
- 好吧 開始大干一場吧！
- All right, let's do it!
好吧 太棒了 讓我來教你這個怎么用
Okay, great. Let me show you how to fly this.
你好？ 我是一只鳥
Um, hello? I'm a bird.
我很確定我知道如何...
I'm pretty sure I know how to...
我錯了！ 我完全錯了！
I was wrong! I was immediately wrong!
當然 那個自動飛行按鈕讓你飛得更完美
Of course, the autopilot button. That makes perfect sense.
我知道 我在測試你
I knew that. I was testing you.
你測試了一個讓我成功做到了的事
Oh, you were testing me on a thing that I made.
- 那當然  - 你的座位濕嗎？
- That's correct. - Is your seat wet?
是的 那是我的尿
Yep. That's my urine.
我在下降的時候拉了點尿在座位上
I peed in the seat when we were falling.
你還想說些其他的什么嗎？
Whoo. What else do you want to talk about?
我的孩子
My baby.
現在 我真的覺得你會喜歡上這間房子貝基
Now, I really think you're gonna love this one, Becky.
我們都覺得你這次找到了 適合你的房子
I think we found you a good one.
是啊 當你看到這個房子
Yeah, when we saw this,
我們當時選房子的時候 就是“哇”  就是這間 的這種感覺
we looked at each other and we were like, "Wow."
當然我在說你們的房子
"This is theirs." Yeah.
- 只不過可能要裝修一下  -  是啊
- And it's a fixer-upper... - Yeah. It is.
我知道裝修不是你們要的
...which I know we weren't looking for.
但是至少它不是破爛不堪
But at least it's not a fixer-downer.
親愛的 你能不能...
Oh, honey, can you just...
- 你可不可以等一下？  - 是的 你可以嗎？
- Can you hold one second? - Yeah, can you?
- 你去看看  - 什么？ 不 還沒輪到我
- You're up. You're up.  - What? No, it's not my turn.
- 你去 馬上   - 不行啊
- You're up, now. You're up. - It can't be.
所以你是想我們的家被毀 對嗎
So you want a panic room, okay.
內特？
Nate?
干嘛？
What?
內特？
Nate?
在這 伙計
Hey there, buddy.
你在干什么？
Whatcha doin' here?
我正在準備
I'm preparing.
很好 你正在準備
Right, you're preparing.
準備什么？
For what?
迎接送子鳥送來的我的弟弟
To get my baby brother from the storks.
好吧
Right.
我喜歡你校鼓勵超越現實的想象力
Hey, I love your school encourages imagination over actual learning,
- 但是送子鳥已經不能再遞送寶寶了  - 我知道
- but the storks don't deliver anymore.  - I know.
它們從來就沒有遞送過寶寶  就像是 永遠都沒有
They haven't done that in, like, forever.
爸爸 你根本不需要幫助我
Dad, you don't have to help me at all.
我就是要讓覺得回去工作會內疚
This is a guilt-free pass for you to go back inside and work.
你走就可以了
Just go.
- 走 走吧 爸爸 - 什么？
- Go. Shoo, shoo, Dad. Go. - What?
好吧 那我走了
Okay, all right. Fine.
你眨眨眼我就進大學了
You blink and I'll be in college.
你說什么
What was that?
我只是一直走 一直工作
Hmm? No, I'm just walking, working.
- 我什么都沒說 你只需要...  - 好吧
- I didn't say anything. You should just... - Okay.
還記得還當我是個嬰兒的時候嗎？ 這就像一分鐘之前？
Remember when I was a baby? It felt like one minute ago?
- 什么？  - 什么？
- What? - What?
好
Fine.
爸爸 你就是我的偶像 不過最多兩年 以后我就不會這么覺得了
Dad, you'll be my idol for, like, two more years.
好吧 我聽到了
Okay, I heard that one.
這樣吧  聽著
Okay. All right, look.
五分鐘 我就只有五分鐘 然后我們就停止
Five minutes. That's all the time I have is five minutes, and then we stop.
好 五分鐘
Yeah, five minutes.
五分鐘 然后...
Five minutes, and then...
我們就停下來
We stop.
五分鐘之后我們就停止
Five minutes and then we stop.
什么？
What?
粉末？
Powder?
嬰兒粉
Baby powder.
我鴿子的味覺又回來了
Homing pigeon powers activate!
寶貝 我們要怎么叫你呢 寶貝？
Baby, what are we gonna call you, baby?
這太瘋狂了 我們正在遞送一個嬰兒！
This is crazy. We are delivering a baby!
不 我們正在遞送一個包裹
No, we are delivering a package.
可能我們應該給它取個名字而不是叫它“包裹”
Maybe we should name it instead of calling it "the package."
我們不給包裹起名字 好嗎？
We do not name the package, okay?
這很簡單
It's very simple.
我們制定一個計劃 就要死守計劃
We make a plan. Stick to the plan.
用生命遞送
Always deliver.
然后我們就回去 董事會就會任命我為老板了
And then we get back to Storkcon so the board can name me boss.
這太刺激了
Oh, it's so exciting.
我們可以從老板朱尼爾那得到什么期望嗎？
What can we expect from boss Junior?
你知道那是最高機密
Oh, you know that's top secret.
- 你可以告訴我的 來嘛  - 我要做的事情太大了
- You can tell me. Come on. - It's gonna be big!
比如說 到底有多大 你到底要干什么？
Like what? Like, what, how big? Like, what are you gonna do?
現在最好不再討論這件事了
I prefer not to talk about it right now.
- 你不知道嗎？  - 什么？
- Do you not know? - What?
-天吶 你不知道  - 我知道
- Oh, my gosh. You don't know.  - I know.
如果你不知道 那為什么你要成為一個老板？
If you don't know, then why do you wanna be boss?
- 我知道  - 你不知道
- I know. - You don't.
我覺得你笑得好假
Oh, man, you laugh when you're uncomfortable.
不
No.
- 是我按到了什么開關了嗎？  - 不是
- Am I pushing your buttons?  - Uh, no.
- 是的  - 不是
- Yes, I am. - Nah. No.
- 嗶 嗶 嗶 嗶  - 不 那些都不是我的按鈕
- Beep, beep, boop, boop... - No, those aren't even where my buttons
如果我有按鈕
would be if I had buttons.
- 嗶 嗶 咘 咘...  - 不錯的嘗試
- Beep, beep, boop, boop... - So, nice try.
我正在編程你要告訴我為什么你想當一個老板
I am programming you to tell me why you want to be boss.
我喜歡機器 所以這很有趣
I love robots, so this is fun.
我們有共同擁有一個美好時光
We're having a good time together.
你為什么想要成為一個老板？
Why do you wanna be boss? Why do you wanna be boss?
別說了！
Back off!
天啊！ 不！
Oh, God! No!
不
No, no, no!
哇！  這很有趣
Wow! Well, that was funny.
你差點就死了
You almost died.
我猜今天我們上的那堂課是別問為什么我想要成為一個老板 對嗎？
I guess the lesson we learned today is don't ask me why I want to be boss, right?
是啊 很好的一節課
Okay, good talk.
很好的一節課
Good talk.
那聽起來不是很高興
That didn't sound happy.
其實 我們很快就到了
Yeah, well, the package will be delivered soon enough.
我真的在想我們應該好好檢查一下那個東西 你知道
I really think that we should check that out, you know.
只要放輕松就好了
Ah, just relax.
好吧 你是對的
Okay. Yeah, you're right.
你看 包裹在自己哭著輕輕入睡
Ah, you see, the package has cried itself gently to sleep.
我不能接受！
I can't take it!
我控制不了我的身體！ 必須去打開那個包裹！
Can't help body movements! Must open pod!
等一下！ 不！
Wait! No!
包裹！ 一定要打開包裹！
The pod! Gotta open the pod!
別  快回來！ 回來！
Oh, no! No, no, no! Come back! Come back!
- 快到駕駛座那里  - 把飛機拉起來
- Be there in a jiff!  - Pull yourself together!
- 快回來就是飛機   -我要去打開這個包裹！
- Fly this plane!  - Gotta open the pod!
我們要死啦！
We're gonna die!
好吧 至少孩子安靜下來了
Well, at least the baby's quiet.
你是失去理智了嗎？
Are you out of your mind?
因為孩子哭你就撞毀一架飛機？
A baby cries and you crash a plane?
我在忙著這個包裹的事情！
Hey, hey, hey! I was busy with the pod!
為什么你不開啟自動駕駛？
Why didn't you turn on the autopilot?
我當時慌了！ 聽我說 小郁
I was panicking! Listen to me, Tulip.
- 你撞毀了飛機一架飛機 聽到我說的了嗎？  - 但是孩子安靜下來了
- You crashed a plane, did you hear me?  - The baby is quiet.
- 你撞毀了一架飛機！  - 孩子安靜了啊！
- You crashed a plane!  - The baby is quiet!
- 那孩子安靜了嗎？  - 是的 她安靜了！
- The baby is quiet?  - The baby is quiet!
- 為什么你什么不早說？  - 不！
- Why didn't you say anything? - Oh, no!
為什么那么安靜？
Why is it quiet?
打開們 打開門
Open the pod! Open the pod! Open the pod! Open the pod!
要怎么打開這個？ 快點！
How do you open this thing? How do you open it? Come on!
天吶 你知道我剛才想到了什么嗎？
Oh, my gosh. You know what I just realized?
這個孩子和我是同一天生日
This baby and I have the same birthday.
不 我才不在乎呢
Oh, yeah. I don't care.
你撞毀了這架飛機 我再也不需要你了
You crashed the plane. I don't need you anymore.
我要自己去遞送這個孩子了 再見
I'm going to deliver the package myself. Goodbye.
什么？ 你要叛離這個團隊嗎？
What? You're breaking up the team?
“團隊”？ 你有病吧？
"Team"? What is wrong with you?
我和你從來就不是一個團隊 我們之間你什么都沒有
You and I are not a team. We are nothing.
這里沒有“我們”
There is no "we."
這全都是你的錯 這個
This is all your fault. This.
這個 還有這個！
This. This!
全是你的錯
All of this.
祝你好運 孤兒小郁
A good day to you, Orphan Tulip.
祝你好運
A good day.
好吧 和往常一樣 我會很好的
Well, just so you know, I'll be fine.
我是信件整理部門最受歡迎的人
I'm the most popular person in the entire Letter Sorting department.
- 我聽不清你說的！  - 我說...
- I can't hear you! - I said that...
這聽起來就像口吃
Yeah, it just sounds
like "Blah, blah, blah,"
還混雜著哭聲
but mixed with crying.
但是那不是我...朱尼爾 快來這里
But that's not what I'm... Junior, come here.
我聽不清你在說什么 不過我知道你肯定是在狡辯
I can't hear what you're saying, but I assume it's lame.
我說我是最受歡迎的人...
I said I'm the most popular person...
別說了！
Lame!
小郁是個傻瓜
Tulip's dumb.
我有一個你不適合這份工作的原因
There's a reason she doesn't fit in.
如果你有建造一架飛機的本領 那么干嘛會摧毀它？
If you're smart enough to build a plane, then who wrecks one?
我要去遞送這個孩子 然后立刻回到山上
I'm gonna deliver this package and be back at Stork Mountain in no time.
太好了 我被狼群包圍了！
Oh, great. Now I'm surrounded by wolves!
你們準備干什么 敲暈我？
What are you gonna do, knock me unconscious?
完美！
Perfect!
這在逗我嗎？
Oh, seriously?
我不是在和你說話 我在生你的氣！
I'm not talking to you. I'm mad at you!
真的嗎？ 那我要做什么？
Oh, no. Really? What am I gonna do?
我們沒話聊了！ 聊天結束
We are done! This conversation is over.
最后一句話是我說的！
Last word, me!
- 最后一句話  - 是我說的
- Last word. - Me.
- 最后一句話   - 我說的
- Last word. Last word. - Me. Me. Me.
聽著 我是首領
Listen, I'm the alpha.
我要第一個吃這個寶貝
I'm gonna eat this thing first.
我要做新首領
I'm gonna be the new alpha.
不 這里... 不需要新首領
No. There is no... There's no need for a new alpha.
我是首領！
I'm the alpha!
- 你...  - 你甚至連老二的都排不上
- You...  - You're not even a beta.
我是首領！
I'm the alpha!
不 你不是首領！
No, you're not the alpha!
剛剛發生什么了？
What just happened?
- 那是什么？  - 你剛剛做了什么？
- What was that? - What did that thing just do?
- 等一下  我們在干嘛
- I'm sorry. Where were we?
我要吞沒這家伙
I'm gonna devour this thing.
我要把她的手臂咬下來
I'm gonna bite her arm clean off.
你沒有把她的手臂咬下來
You didn't bite her arm clean off.
那嘗起來像花一樣
This tastes like flowers.
好吧 站一邊去
Okay, stand aside.
看看你 看看你都干了什么
Look at you. Look what you did.
你做了和你一樣的事
I did the same thing you did.
- 你愛上她了嗎  - 我愛上她了
- Are you in love? - I am in love.
- 你也愛上她了  - 我也愛上她了
- Are you in love?  - I'm in love, too.
我同意
I agree. I agree. I agree. I agree.
伙計們！
Hey, guys!
這個小東西現在是我們狼群的新成員
This tiny thing is now a wolf, everybody.
- 你說什么？  - 什么？ 發生什么事了？
- What did he say?  - What? What's happening?
- 大聲點 我們聽不見！  - 她是我們的人了！
- Louder. We're in the back!  - We're keeping it!
- 在后面的 她是我們的人！  - 好 謝謝
- Back of the pack, we're keeping it! - Okay, thank you.
看那個
Aw, look at that.
這個遞送任務現在完成了
The delivery is now complete.
現在 我只要找到路離開這里
Now, I just need to find a way out of here.
等一下 你不是在遞送她到她父母那嗎？
Wait, you're not gonna deliver her to her actual parents?
嬰兒不知道有什么不同 因為嬰兒是傻子
Baby doesn't know the difference because babies are dumb.
嬰兒不是傻子
Oh, babies are not dumb.
他們超傻的
They are super dumb.
嬰兒能解決甚至我們都不理解的問題
Babies have a higher level of intelligence than we will ever understand.
你應該像一個嬰兒一樣學習如何說話
You sound like a baby that learned how to talk.
我是個嬰兒要學說話！
I am a baby that learned how to talk!
嘿 我想教她走一個圓
Hey, I want to teach it to walk around in circles
- 在她躺下之前  - 好啊
- before it lays down.  - Yes. Yes. Yes.
那是我最愛教的事
That's my favorite thing to teach.
別靠太近 你嚇著她了！
Don't get too close, you're gonna scare it!
我不是...
I'm not... Ow!
- 嗯 這個寶寶 她在笑！  - 是啊 笑笑比較容易被接納
- Huh. The baby, it's laughing!  - Yeah. Good for it.
不
No.
好吧 我對我將要做的事感到抱歉
Okay, I apologize for what I'm about to do.
- 對不起
- Sorry.
- 停下！  - 對不起
- Stop it!  - Sorry.
對不起
Sorry.
- 那是我的臉！  - 對不起！
- That's my face!  - Sorry!
- 你為什么還不停下？  - 快點！
- Why did you stop?  - Come on!
好吧 我有一個計劃 我可以假裝
Okay, I get the plan. I can fake it. I can fake it!
好  那就假裝！
Okay, okay. Fake it!
等一下！等一下 好嗎？ 等一下
Wait! Hold on a second, okay? Wait.
好了 我有一個主意
All right, I have an idea.
你們可以想像得到 如果你把我們放下來他會用多大的力來打我
Imagine how much harder she could hit me if you cut us down.
太好了！ 我真的可以為這家伙痛哭
Oh, yeah! I could really wail on this guy.
我的意思是 你并不需要做到那樣 但是...
I mean, you don't have to go that hard, but...
- 我想我會的  - 好吧...
- Oh, I think I do.  - Well...
我還在生你的氣
Oh, I'm still mad at you.
切斷它！
Cut 'em down!
抓住一根棒子或其它也行！
Grab a stick or something!
等一下 什么？
Wait, what?
你要想更多嗎？
Do you want more?
是的！
Yeah!
這根小樹枝足夠嗎？
Will this tiny twig be enough?
- 是的！  - 不！ 不！
- Yes!  - No! No!
要更大的！
Bigger!
你可以找到最大的樹干！
Get the biggest twig you can find!
對不起了 朱尼爾 我只能給予它們想要的東西了
Sorry, Junior. Gotta give the people what they want.
抓住那個孩子！ 快！
Grab the baby! Let's go!
群狼聽令 抓住他們！
Wolf pack, chase!
抓住他們
Chase, chase, chase.
為什么你不停止打我？
Why wouldn't you stop hitting me?
我在讓它們分心啊
I was distracting them.
好吧 我們快走吧
Okay, here we go.
我們應該砍斷這索橋！
Oh! Oh! We should untie the bridge!
是的 我知道 不然你以為我要干嘛？
Yeah, I know. What do you think I'm doing?
抓住他們
Chase, chase, chase.
唔啊
Whoa, whoa, whoa...
滾吧 臭狼們！
Suck it, wolves!
群狼聽令！ 開啟過橋模式！
Wolf pack! Form of wolf bridge!
發生什么事了？
What is happening?
那群浪在搭建一個懸浮橋
The wolves are forming a suspension bridge.
- 這怎么可能？  - 我也不知道
- How is that possible? - I don't know.
好吧 我們走！
All right, let's go!
一座橋！
A bridge!
我們有可能會死啊！
We're probably gonna die!
抓住他們
Chase, chase, chase!
快走！
Let's go!
- 那扇門掉了！  - 別管它了！
- The door!  - Leave it!
快要抓到了
Almost gotcha, almost gotcha, almost gotcha!
我的天吶 我們可以用那東西充當一個東西！
Oh, my gosh! We can use that thing as a thing!
對！ 充當一個東西
Right! To thing to the thing!
快走！
Let's go!
- 你聽起來像一個猴子  - 你聽起來才像一個猴子！
- You sound like a monkey. - You sound like a monkey!
群狼聽令 開啟船艇模式！
Wolf pack, form of wolf boat!
船艇模式！
Boat!
你們在開玩笑嗎？
Are you kidding me?
那太荒謬了！
That is so unpredictable!
哈哈！
Ha-ha!
群狼聽令！ 開啟潛艇模式！
Wolf pack! Form of submarine!
潛艇模式！
Submarine!
我不知道原來狼群可以變成一艘潛艇！
I didn't know wolves could form a submarine!
我以前都沒有見到過這樣的事情
I've never seen that before on nature shows.
好 快點 快到那架飛機那！
Okay, quick, get to the plane!
什么？ 我以為它已經壞掉了
What? I thought it was broken.
不 我之前修理了幾個部分了
No, I fixed it with some spare parts.
我們快到了 我們快到了
We're gonna get ya. We're gonna get ya.
好 快走！
All right, let's go!
朱尼爾！
Junior!
顯而易見的 我沒辦法按下這個按鈕
Obviously, I'm not gonna push it.
等一下！
Wait!
或許我可以輕輕的按下它
Oh, I could push it so easily.
這會用到那么稍微小小的武力
It would take such a little amount of force.
別那樣看著我
Don't look at me like that.
如果你不給我們那個小家伙 我們會吃掉你的
If you don't give us Tiny Thing, we're gonna eat you.
我們無論如何都會吃掉你的！
We're gonna eat you anyway!
你別那么說
You don't say it.
你得先做個交易 然后你再吃掉他們
You make the deal and then you eat them anyway.
知道了
Gotcha!
我們不打算吃掉你！
We're not going to eat you!
現在說這句太晚了！
Well, now it's too late!
不！ 不！
Oh, no! No!
- 朱尼爾！  - 快走！
- Junior!  - Let's go!
好了 開始飛吧！
All right, let's fly!
這還是不能飛啊
It doesn't fly.
- 什么？  - 它要掉下去了！
- What? - It falls!
為什么我要救你？
Why did I save you?
群狼聽令！ 開啟飛機模式！
Wolf pack! Form of wolf plane!
- 快點！ 快點！  - 我們走吧！
- Come on! Come on!  - Let's go!
小家伙 快回來！
Tiny Thing, come back!
回來 小家伙 我們需要你！
Oh, come back, Tiny Thing. We need you!
我的孩子
My baby.
什么鬼？
What?
再多五分鐘 然后我們就停止
Five more minutes and then we stop
你們在干嘛？
What?
- 再多5分鐘...  - 不！
- Five more minutes... - No!
那是我們的煙囪！
That's our chimney!
你們準備摧毀整個屋頂啊？
You're gonna destroy the whole roof?
媽媽 我們不得不把這個煙囪換成一個滑滑梯了
Mom, we have to replace the chimney with a slide
為了送子鳥給我遞送來的小弟弟
for when the storks deliver my baby brother.
他說什么
What he said.
不！ 別瘋了 你不可能做到的
No! Don't be crazy. You cannot do the chimney.
來嘛 別讓我讓我做個吝嗇的媽媽
Come on, don't make me the mean mom.
- 爸爸很有趣 媽媽很吝嗇  - 我聽到了！
- Dads are fun, moms are mean. - I heard that!
- 父母會議  - 集合！
- Parent conference. - Pinching!
海倫 人們可能覺得我們可能瘋了
Henry, people are gonna think we're crazy.
我們需要告訴他
We need to tell him.
告訴他什么？
Tell him what?
什么？ 給他看多點電視？
What, to go watch more TV?
在我的人生中 我陪伴他的這段時間是我人生中最好的時光
This is the best time I've had with Nate in my life.
我真正地再一次感受到了當爸爸的感覺
I actually feel like a dad again.
然后我們再告訴他小弟弟出現？
And when no baby brother shows up?
是啊 然后我們就告訴他
Well, then we tell him.
我們可以換得一個新的煙囪
We can get a new chimney,
但是我再也不可能有這樣的時間陪伴內特了
but we'll never be able to replace this time with Nate.
如果我們繼續帶著頭上的耳機
And if we put those headsets back on,
我們在內特多少歲時候才取下來？
how old will Nate be when we take them off again?
我已經不是一個小孩子了
I'm not a jerky teen yet.
飛逝的時光 寶貴的記憶
Fleeting moments, precious memories.
媽媽也很有趣
Moms are fun, too.
哇！ 這看起來只是一個豆腐渣工程
Wow! That's... That's not a well-made chimney.
我...我并不是個女漢子
I'm... I'm a small woman and that just came...
是啊！ 這太對了！
Yeah, that came right down!
好了 接下來該做什么？
Okay, so, uh, what's next?
好 現在是周六的晚上
Okay, it's Saturday night.
只要我們明天送到 我們仍然可以去參加大會
As long as we deliver by tomorrow, we can still make it for Storkcon Monday.
感謝你為了就我 而折回去
Thanks for waiting for me back there.
我不知道你在說什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
“我付有男子的氣概地承認所有的任何事”
Oh, okay, "I'm too manly to admit anything at all about anything."
那應該是我嗎？
Is that supposed to be me?
不好意思 “這是個更準確的陳述”
Oh, sorry, "This is a more accurate representation."
你太對了 那就是我想聽到的
Oh, you're so right. That is what I sound like.
讓我們就像這樣聊
Let's both talk like this.
寶寶現在很激動
Baby's fussing.
她很無聊呢 我們必須使她分心
She's bored. We have to distract her.
讓我來試試
Oh, let's see. Oh!
你是個寶寶 你是個寶寶
You are a baby You are a baby
小手   小腳丫
Little hands, little feet
- 看看你 你真的好可愛啊  - 停下！ 停下！ 停下！
- Look at you, you're so sweet
- Stop! Stop! Stop!
你太可愛了 以致使我要...
You're so cute I wanna...
我們一起到處走走吧 好嗎？
Let's just step aside, all right?
- 讓我來  - 你想給她唱首歌？
- And let me do it. - You want to sing to her?
是的 是不是很驚訝呢？
Yeah. Is that so surprising?
事實上 我是個優秀的歌手
I'm a pretty good singer, actually.
好了！ 唱吧
Okay, fine! Sing to her.
當你想要一些東西
When you need a little something
但有太多的事情要做
And there's too much to do
只要用你的小手輕輕點擊一下 我們就會給你運送快遞
Just click your little finger And we'll ship it for you
角落商店 角落商店公司
Cornerstore, Cornerstore. com
阿拉斯加和夏威夷不接受免費運送
Free shipping does not apply in Alaska and Hawaii.
等一下 這是歌嗎？
Wait, wait, wait, is that a song?
那不是歌 那是廣告
That's not a song, that's an ad.
- 好 為了生活拼命工作吧 小郁  - 好吧
- Well, strap in for this one then, Tulip. - Okay.
角落商店
Cornerstore
我喜歡這故事的發展
I like how this is going.
讓你的包裹落在我的身上
Let your packages rain down on me
這看起來像是一個可供晚上休息的地方
Uh, this looks like a good place to rest for the night.
朱尼爾 你在說什么？ 為什么你在自言自語...
Junior, what are talking about? Why are you acting...
我聽不到你在說什么
I can't hear what you're saying.
- 朱尼爾？  - 我聽不到！
- Junior?  - I can't hear you!
朱尼爾！
Junior!
你有沒有看到過一個紅色頭的女士和一只鳥？
Hey! Have you seen a red-headed lady and a stork?
一只鳥和一位女士？
A bird and a lady?
我不知道你在說什么
I don't know what you're talkin' about.
前幾天 我看見有兩個有著符合你描述的人！
I saw two that fit that description the other day!
不 我不會成為你的朋友
No, man, I will not be your friend.
對不起 我想我要離開了
Sorry, thought we were vibing.
為什么你變得那么可怕？
Why you being so creepy?
你知道嗎？ 就...這 這
You know what? Just get... Here. Here.
我只想把這東西放這兒
I'm just gonna put this right here.
這里發生什么了？
What happened back there?
什么？ 你什么意思？
What? What do you mean?
你刺破了那艘船？ 怎么看都說不通啊
Uh, you stabbed the raft? For literally no reason!
這不是沒有理由的 只不過是個私人的理由
It was not for no reason. It was for personal reasons.
不管怎樣 那個海岸上有一個港口
Anyways, there's a port right there on the coast.
我們早上要做的第一件事就是離開這里
We'll just leave first thing in the morning
然后繼續遞送包裹
and deliver the package.
請叫它“寶寶”
Just call it "the baby."
為什么你對嬰兒感到如此害怕？
Why are you so afraid of babies?
因為這個包裹
Because this one single package
會毀滅關聯著我整個人生的工作！
could ruin everything I've worked towards my entire life!
- 為什么你又想著當老板？  - 不是又
- Why do you wanna be boss again? - Not this again.
不 真的 為什么你總想做角落商店的老板呢？
No, really. Why do you wanna be boss of Cornerstore?
我不知道 好了嗎？ 我是說...
I don't know, okay? I mean...
為什么每個人都想做老板？
Why does anyone want to be boss?
這是規定好的 這就是原因
It rules. That's why.
是啊 但是你又會做什么？
Yeah, but what would you do?
- 我不知道 你會做什么？  - 我很高興你提出的問題！
- I don't know. What would you do? - I'm glad you asked!
好 第一 我會雇用一堆做運送的鳥和其他動物
Well, for one, I would employ a more diverse variety of birds and animals.
第二 我會除去角落商店的不良安置
Two, I would get rid of the Cornerstore warehouse
因為那個建筑就是個失敗品
because that building is a bummer.
第三 我會再次開始遞送寶寶
And three, I would start delivering babies again.
好了 你對這個問題做了很多準備呀
Okay, you were very prepared for that question.
我感覺我離你太近了
Man, I feel so close to you.
就像我們是閨蜜一樣
Like we're girlfriends already.
好吧 我知道我說完那句話后
All right, I knew as I was saying it
就應該閉上嘴
that I should just keep my mouth shut.
我想立即給你的羽毛編編發！
Aw, I want to braid
your feathers immediately!
看
Look, uh...
耶？
Yeah?
現在真正的坦誠相待時 我告訴你為什么我建造了那架飛機
While we're being real honest right now, I'll tell you why I built my plane.
那不是用來為角落商店遞送包裹的
It's not to deliver packages for Cornerstore.com.
我建造它就是為了能找到我的父母
I built my plane to find my parents.
但是我想你不知道你的父母在哪里
But I thought you didn't know where your parents lived.
當賈斯伯摧毀了我的定位器時 我失去了所有的碎片
When Jasper destroyed my homing beacon, I lost all the pieces.
除了這一片
Except one.
我就在想 運氣好的話也許能夠找到我的父母
And I thought this, plus some luck might be enough to find my parents.
所以說 你是為了這個孩子而犧牲飛機的嗎
So, you sacrificed your plane for this baby?
- 是啊  - 為什么？
- Yeah.  - Why?
我不知道 我猜如果這個孩子找到了她的家庭
Oh, I don't know. I guess if this baby finds her family,
我的意思是 這很值
I mean, it's worth it.
是吧？
Right?
好吧 你可以給她起名字了
Fine. You can name her.
- 真的嗎？  - 是的 來吧
- Really?  - Yeah, go ahead.
小石頭
Diamond Destiny.
好吧 我改變主意了 你不能給她起名字
Okay, I changed my mind. You can't name her.
太遲了！ 她的名字就是小石頭  就是這個！
Too late! Her name is Diamond Destiny.  Yes, it is!
我說這要是個 像個 真實的名字
I thought it was gonna be, like, an actual name.
這就是啊 小石頭就是她的名字！
It is a name. Diamond Destiny is her name!
有什么不對的嗎 小石頭？
Isn't that right, Diamond Destiny?
我們要幫你找到你的父母咯 一切都會很順利的
We're gonna find your parents, and everything is gonna be just perfect.
你會找到你的家
You'll find your family.
你想嗎？
You think?
當然
For sure.
晚安
Good night.
晚安！
Good night!
發生什么了？ 我起床了
What is it? I'm up.
你覺得她是不是餓了？
Do you think she's hungry?
我不知道
Yeah. I don't know.
可能她需要搖一搖
Uh, maybe she just needs to be rocked.
好吧
Okay.
天吶
Oh, my gosh.
她的眼睛不能再打開了
Her eyes could not be more open.
好吧 抓住那頭
Okay, grab that end.
這就像我們是一家人
It's like we're a family.
我們不像一家人
We are not like a family.
我們就是兩個正在哄寶寶睡覺的兩個人
We're just a guy and a girl trying to put our baby to sleep.
就讓他在這里睡吧
Let's just put her to sleep.
快點 快合上
Come on, close, close, close.
好了 合上 合上 合上 合上
Okay, close. Close, close, close.
這太棒了 對吧？ 她合上雙眼了嗎？
That's good, right? Is that closed enough?
不！ 看 我還能看見她的眼球
No! Look, I can still see eyeball.
我們能用手來讓她的眼睛閉上嗎？ 這里
Can we manually close them? Here.
不！ 別那樣做！ 你在干什么？
No! Don't do that! What are you doing?
我只是想...等一下！ 給我眼睛粘合劑
I'm gonna... Wait! Okay, give me the eye glue.
- 什么？  - 你知道 就是為了讓眼睛合起來那種
- What? - You know, for gluing eyes shut.
不 我們沒有這東西
No, we don't have any.
要粘上了
It's gonna stick.
如果她絕不睡覺怎么辦？
What if she never goes to sleep?
你知道嗎？ 我搞定她了
All right, you know what? I got her.
你去睡覺吧 你去睡覺 這沒問題
You just go to bed. You go to bed. It's fine.
不 在你起床之前 我不會去睡覺 我不是很好
No, I don't wanna go to bed if you're gonna be up. I'll feel bad.
我知道 但是如果我去睡覺了
I know. But if I go to bed,
我會感覺很愧疚的  所以我不能睡覺
then I'm gonna feel guilty. And I just can't.
不 按我說的去做 聽我的
No, that's what I'm saying. Listen to me.
不 所以這就是你去睡覺的原因 而讓我來照顧她
No, so that's why you go to bed, and I'll take care of her.
好吧 我要睡了
All right. I'll go to bed.
我不能相信你真的睡了！
I can't believe you went to bed!
什么？你剛剛說了讓我安心去睡的啊！
What? You just said it was okay for me to go bed!
好吧 你知道什么？
Okay, you know what?
我們可以把她放在手臂上搖晃嗎？
Can we just rock her in our arms?
不 不能 這個沒有愛的小寶寶
No. We do not. No loving the baby.
你說剛剛說了“寶寶”
You said "baby."
好吧 我才不在乎 我一點都不在乎
Fine. I don't care. I don't care.
你喜歡她
You love it.
再見 大兄弟！
Goodbye, brah!
現在喜歡我了么？
How you like me now? Huh!
“現在喜歡我了么？”
"How you like me now"?
現在喜歡我了么？
How you like me now?
How do you like me now!
曾經有一段時間
Now there was a time
那時 你那么喜歡我
When you loved me so
我并沒有做錯
I could do no wrong
現在你要知道的
And now you need to know
停止舞蹈
Dance break!
現在喜歡我了么？
How you like me now? How you like me now?
你確定你都看到了？
And you're sure you saw this?
是的 我確定我都看到了
Yes, I'm sure I saw this.
好吧 我們保持低調
All right. Let's keep this quiet.
是的 先生
Yes, sir.
感謝你的忠誠
Thank you for your loyalty, Pigeon Toady.
或者應該叫你老板
Or should I say boss.
酷
Cool, cool, cool.
蒸汽房在電梯里 真的不可思議！
Whoa! Steam room in an elevator. Mind blown!
閉嘴！ 我在計劃中
Shut up! I'm planning.
那太酷了
Oh, that's cool.
好了 現在 聽著
All right. Now, listen.
首先 我們必須阻止那個遞送
First, we have to stop that delivery.
但是我們不知道他們要去哪
But we don't know where they're headed.
事實上 我們不會跟著他們
Indeed. We won't go to them.
我會讓他們...
We'll make them...
跟著我們
Come to us.
對！
Yes!
好 我走了
Well, I'm off.
你怎么突然就穿上衣服了
You're in a suit suddenly.
走吧
Let's go.
我的毛巾被吹走了
My towel blew away.
朱尼爾
Junior.
快醒醒 我們得走了
Wake up. We gotta go.
我還在睡夢中啊
I'm still asleep.
我知道 但是我們必須得趕路了
I know, we gotta go, we gotta go.
再讓我睡一小會兒
Just let me sleep a little longer.
寶寶已經醒了 船要開了 快起來
Junior. Baby's awake. Ship's leaving. Let's go!
你去就好啦 反正寶寶在你的手上
You do it. You get the baby.
我也很累好不好 不是只有你累
Junior, I'm tired, too!
寶寶是你自己弄出來的 這不能怪我啊
You made it, you get it.
我真棒
Yes!
鉆石啊 快到我這里來
Diamond Destiny, you come back here right now.
我不想再到處跑了
I'm not fooling around.
好啦 我們要坐船走了
All right, let's go. We got a boat to catch.
好耶 我們要去坐船了
We got a boat to catch, oh!
我們走吧
Here we go. On it.
回家咯！
Home stretch!
我們必要要保持絕對的安靜
We have to be absolutely silent.
要是有一個人看見我們帶著小孩我們就完了
One human sees a stork with a baby and we'll get reported.
好了 這是最后一個了 趕快搬上去吧
All right, last one. Let's pack it up.
那是什么
What was that?
聽起來像一個寶寶
Sounds like a baby.
那里看起來不是很對勁
That's very suspicious.
- 他到底在干嘛？  - 我不知道啊
- Why is she doing that?
- I don't know.
拉尿？
Diaper?
不是
Check.
餓了？
Food?
不是
Check.
她可能是困了
Maybe she needs a nap.
睡吧 睡吧 我親愛的寶貝
Rock-a-bye baby, on the treetop
不是  她到底想要什么啊？
Nope. What is it? What does she want?
聲音好像是從那里來的
It's coming from over there!
我不確定 他好像要你抱抱
I don't know. She's reaching for you.
可能她只是想要你
Maybe she just wants you.
不 這不可能
No. That doesn't make sense.
講道理 他現在應該很開心才對啊
Technically, she should be perfectly happy.
我們要怎么辦？
What are we gonna do? What are we gonna do?
我完全沒有頭緒
I have no idea.
不
Oh, no!
別
Oh, no.
她就要哭出來了！
She's gonna blow! She's gonna blow!
我們到底要那她怎么辦
What do I do with her?
抱他 快點！
Take her, take her. Just take her!
噢 看
Ah, look at that.
事實上看起來不錯啊
Actually seems to be working pretty well.
她真好聞
Ha! She smells so nice!
誰有你這么漂亮的眼睛啊 你有啊
Who's got the little  eyes? You do.
你有啊
You do.
不 那船要離岸了
Oh, no! The boat's leaving!
不 不  快走
No, no, no! Come on!
群狼聽令  開啟貨車模式！
Wolf pack. Form of wolf minivan!
貨車模式
Minivan!
給我！
Give me a break!
我的寶寶
My baby!
耶 我們拿到了這個小東西
Ah! We got the Tiny Thing!
這樣對寶寶來說不安全
This is not a safe way to transport the baby.
- 我們現在是父母了  - 開慢點
- We're parents now.   - Just go slower.
- 你說的對   - 慢點
- You're right, you're right, you're right. - Slower.
很好
Okay, good.
小東西 你覺得好嗎？
Is that good, Tiny Thing?
小東西？
Hmm? Tiny Thing?
我們又弄丟她了
We lost her again!
快點 我們穿過這里還是可以趕得上船的
Quick! We can get to the boat through here.
等等 你怎么跑得這么奇怪
Wait. Why are you running so weird?
有什么是我不知道的？
What don't I know?
我的老對手
My old nemesis.
玻璃
"Glass."
鳥兒們是看不到玻璃的
Birds can't see glass!
把那個小東西給我們
Give us Tiny Thing.
快走 小郁 我已經來不及了
Just go, Tulip. It's too late for me.
你現在必須一個人去送她回家了
You've got the baby. you can deliver her yourself.
什么？ 不 我才不要把你丟下
What? No, I'm not leaving you behind!
我們可以戰勝困難的  只要我們一起
We can do this. Together!
那個小東西在哪里？
Where's the Tiny Thing?
- 好吧 小郁 你贏了   - 小東西！ 小東西！
- All right. Tulip, you got this! - Tiny Thing! Tiny Thing!
- 好的 左  右 直走   - 那個小東西在哪里？
- Okay, left. Right. Straight. - Where's the Tiny Thing?
直走 然后 左  右
Straight! Left! Right!
噢 不 我慌了
Oh, no! I'm panicking!
還是右 不 我的意思是左
Uh, right again! Left, I mean. Left!
右 我是說右
Right! Right, I mean.
左 左 右 右
Left! Left! Right! Right!
左 左 左 沒錯就是這樣
Left! Left! Left! Right!
左右  不  我的意思是 右左
Rolft! I mean, ralft!
右  左  我說話已經不經大腦了
Right! Left! I'm just shouting words!
這根本沒有用啊
This is not working!
我們做到啦！
Oh-oh! We did that together!
我幾乎每一次都撞到了玻璃
I ran into every piece of glass.
有的時候還不止一次
Some, more than once.
噢  天啊
Oh, jeez.
要是有機會
What are the chances of that?
我希望在玻璃工廠里狂歡
I guess, pretty high in a glass factory.
- 小東西！   - 快走
- Tiny Thing! Tiny Thing! - Come on!
首先 我們先帶走那個小東西
First, we're gonna take Tiny Thing
然后再養大她讓她變強 獨立的女人
and raise her to be a strong, independent woman.
然后 我們就會吃了你
And then, we're gonna eat you.
我們合作的很好
We made a great team.
我的孩子
My baby.
那是我的孩子
That's my baby!
是賈斯柏
It's Jasper!
我的孩子
My baby!
- 不不不     - 我的孩子！
- No, no, no!    - My baby! My baby! My baby!
放開！
Let go!
放開我們
Let go of us!
群狼聽令  啟動...
Wolf pack, form of...
心碎模式
Broken heart!
離我們遠點
Get away from us!
- 遠點！   - 別動！
- Get away!   - Stay back!
- 快滾回家   - 別過來了
- Go home!   - Come on!
別逼我打你
Don't make me hit you!
-  這件事我可以解釋  - 你想都不要想
- Hey, hey, hey! Let me explain! - I don't wanna hear it!
但當你令我變成孤兒的時候 你竟然說這糟透了
When you orphaned me, you said "whoops!"
糟透了！誰能說出這種話啊
Whoops! You said "whoops!" Who does that?
你就不能讓我解釋么
Will you please let me explain?
他根本就不想聽你的解釋　明白嗎？
Hey! She doesn't wanna hear your explanation, guy!
給我退后
Back off!
其實我當時已經愛上你了
I fell in love with you.
那你繼續講下去
Okay, fine.
講道理　我非常八卦　讓我們聽下去
Honestly, I am very curious.　Let's hear it.
他們說做一名送子鳥是很不容易的
Look, they tell you being a stork isn't gonna be easy.
應生命遞送！
Always deliver.
但是我辜負了這個職業
I failed to do that.
你的定位器碎了 碎片掉落在了世界各地
Your beacon broke. The pieces scattered.
我畢生都在尋找
I spent my entire life
尋找那些丟失了的碎片 讓我的孩子可以回家
searching for the missing pieces so that I could deliver my baby.
那么多年拿過去了 我仍然那沒找齊 還差一塊
And yet, after all these years, I'm still missing one piece.
- 但是我過誓了  - 我的天啊  等等
- But, I have pledged...  - Oh, my gosh! Wait.
要成為你的父母 小郁
...to be the parent I took from you, Tulip.
而我會傾盡我的生命
And I will lay down my life.
那個碎片在我身上
I have the missing piece!
等等  你說什么？
Excuse me, what?
那個碎片在我身上
I have the missing piece.
我的家
My home!
我要回家了
I'm going home!
我終于可以見到我的真正的家人了
I'm gonna finally meet my real family.
天啊！
Oh, my gosh!
這太瘋狂了  你能相信嗎？ 朱尼爾
This is crazy! Junior, can you believe it?
是啊  這真的太棒了
No, that's so... That's so great.
你是該走了
Yeah, yeah, you should go.
是啊 當我們送完這個寶寶之后
Oh, yeah, well, after we deliver the baby. But, yeah!
不 不 不  我能照顧好這個寶寶
No, no, no. I can take care of the baby.
不應該走了
You should go now.
不行 我們還沒有完成我們的任務
No, no, no. We have to finish the delivery.
我恨抱歉打擾你們
I'm sorry to cut you off.
你知道嗎？ 搞笑的的 當你說出 真正的家人的時后
You know what's so funny is just then when you said "real family",
我的心如刀割啊
it, like, weirdly hurt my feelings.
但是我意識到我怎么能如此愚蠢
But I realized how stupid that is.
我的意思是 我只是一只鳥 而你是一個人啊
I mean, I'm a bird and you're, like, a sloppy human
而且 這也不是我們的寶寶  只是一個寶寶
and that's not our baby. It's just some baby.
這么說吧  我們的確不像一個家庭 但是我們就像一家人一樣
Well, I mean, we're not, like, a "family", but we are like a family.
這就像 我們不僅是我們 還是這間公司
Well, it's like we are except instead we're more like employees
正在遞送這個寶寶的員工
who are delivering a package, and that's all.
你知道我什么意思嗎？
Do you know what I mean?
你應該要回到那個屬于你的地方了
And you should go to where you belong.
現在 你知道我的意思了嗎
Now. Do you know what I mean?
不 我們是一個團隊 明白嗎 朱尼爾
No! Junior, we are a team, okay?
我們要遞送這個寶寶
We're gonna deliver this baby,
而且要一起去見我們父母
then we're gonna meet my parents,
- 然后我們在帶他們去送房子鳥山上參觀   - 我當時真的就應該直接開除你的
- then I'm gonna show them Stork Mountain. - I was supposed to fire you.
知道嗎
Okay?
我原本要被開除？
You were supposed to fire me?
是啊
Yeah.
應該說是“解放” “自由”  好吧 是開除
Well, "liberate". "Free". Yes, fire.
而我并沒有這么做 沒有讓這些成為現實
And then I didn't, and then this all happened.
聽著 松子鳥山上沒有什么值的你回去的
Look, there's nothing waiting for you back at Stork Mountain.
沒有人在乎
Who cares though?
現在是時候去和你真正的家人重逢
It's time for you to go and meet your real family!
這很凌然激動 不是嗎？
That's exciting, right?
聽著 我...
Look, I...
我只是覺得這樣對你最好 明白嗎？
I just think this is for the best, you know?
這正是你一直所希望的 不是嗎
It's what you've always wanted.
是啊 我渴望見到我的家人
Yeah, I wanna go meet my family.
所以我覺得我最好現在就走
So, yeah, I better go now, I guess.
沒關系 我會照顧好這個寶寶的
It's gonna be fine. I'll take good care of her.
好的  我應該走了
- Okay, okay. - Fine.
再見了 孩子
Goodbye, little girl.
希望你旅途愉快
Have a good trip back home.
你自己小心
You take care...
安全
And be safe.
我害怕
I'm scared.
他們是你的家人 他們會喜歡你的
They're your family. They're going to love you.
我就在這里等你
I'll be right here.
噢 給你的手機
Oh, oh! Give me your camera.
我超愛抓拍這些溫馨的時刻
I'd love to capture this family moment.
好了 我已經在拍了
Okay, camera rolling and action.
你可以的
Yup. Okay.
按門鈴吧
Ring the doorbell.
我沒有聽到門鈴呢
I don't hear a doorbell ringing.
你是對的 讓我們一起見證這個時刻吧
You're right. Let's take our time.
這個時刻我等了一輩子啊
I've only waited my whole life for this!
小郁
Tulip?
是送子鳥
The storks!
噢 天啊！
Oh, boy!
- 我們來了  - 我的天啊！
- Here we go! - Oh, my gosh! Oh, my gosh!
- 記得微笑   - 我現在甚至有點點緊張
- Okay. Big smile! - I'm a little nervous. Okay.
大家冷靜一點
Everyone, calm down!
這些不符合規定
This is not to code.
- 什么？  這個都要撤下來
- What? - This all has to come down.
亨特？
Hunter?
你被開除了  - 但是 但是...
- You're fired! - But, but, but...
但是什么但是  你真是太愚蠢了
"But, but, but..." You are so idiotic!
你怎么就沒發現呢？
How were you not suspicious?
我以為這只是一個高檔社區
I thought it was a gentrifying neighborhood.
沒想到在這里也能見到你啊
Didn't expect to see you here, brah!
沒錯 這是我干的
Oh, yes, I did. I set it up.
把那個東西拿走
Seize the thing!
不 別拿那個寶寶
Wait, no! Not the baby!
別擔心 我們會好好照顧她的
Don't worry. She's gonna be fine.
她會和企鵝在一起的
She's with penguins.
有關于他們作為一個保姆是多么偉大的記錄
They have whole documentaries about how great they are at babysitting.
而且她會是一個優秀的游泳健將
And she'll be an excellent swimmer.
等到她老了我們會送她回到人類的世界的
And then when she's old enough, we'll return her to the human world.
你簡直是瘋了 你應該把她送回家
That's insane! You need to deliver her!
我們不能讓一個新上任的老板頭簍子
We can't let it get out that the new boss accidentally made a baby!
我們的股票會跌停的 我們所建造的一切
Our stock would plummet, everything we've built.
我的整個公司都會倒閉的
My entire company will fall apart!
那些父母是不會發現這一切的
Those parents can never find out.
好了 我們可以走了
Okay, we're ready to go.
現在誰才是寶寶呢
Who's the baby now?
做得好
Good enough.
- 違章建造？   - 為什么
- "Cease and desist"?  - Why?
這不符合我們的規定 確切的說 是很危險
This is not up to code, and quite frankly, it looks dangerous.
我們不能把那些拆掉
We can't tear it down.
因為這樣送子鳥就不會把握弟弟送過來了
'Cause then the storks won't deliver my baby brother.
警察說的對 內特
The policeman's right, Nate.
他們不遞送寶寶了  再也不遞送了
They don't deliver babies. Not anymore.
那我們做這一切的意義在哪里
Then why did we do all this stuff?
因為我們很享受和你在一起
Because we were having such fun playing with you.
親愛的 我們一起度過了這段愉快是時光
Oh, honey. We spent time together.
而這正是意義所在
And that's what matters.
所以這是違法了還是說只是一個警告？
So is this like a ticket thing or a warning thing?
這感覺像是一個警告 對吧
It feels like a warning, right?
是啊 我們已經收到警告了 已經知道自己錯哪了
Yeah, we are warned. We are properly warned.
我能理解你的心情
Oh, buddy.
走吧
Come on.
什么鬼
What?
我的天啊 你還好嗎
Oh, my gosh! Are you okay?
發生什么事了 孩子在哪里
What happened? Where's the baby?
他們綁了我 然后帶走了他
They tied me up and took her.
為什么會覺得這是她的家
Why would you think this was her house?
這附近可都是倉庫啊
It's surrounded by a bunch of scary warehouses!
可是很高檔啊
Gentrification!
他們怎么就帶走她了 你的責任心呢？
How could they just take her? She was your responsibility!
這不是我的錯 好嗎
It wasn't my fault, okay?
我沒有在怪你 我只是在擔心那個寶寶
I'm not blaming you. I'm just worried about the baby!
我也很擔心啊 我就是為什么我在壕叫
Well, I'm also worried, which is why I'm yelling!
我們在嚎叫是因為我們在浪費時間
We're yelling 'cause we're wasting time!
我們要怎么回到角落商店呢
How can we get back to Cornerstore?
你在干嘛？ 購物嗎？
You're shopping? What are you doing?
我明白了  這樣我們就可以躲在箱子里
Oh, I see. You did that so we could hide in the box
快速的回到角落商店了
and get back to Cornerstore real quick.
- 沒錯   - 你真聰明
- That's right.  - Yeah.
等會兒  這里發生什么事了 朱尼爾
Wait a minute. Junior, what is going on?
這是什么鬼
What the heck is this?
這是送子鳥大會
This is Storkcon.
每年 松子鳥們只為這一件事情而相聚到一起
Once a year, storks come together for one thing.
這就是 送子鳥大會
Storkcon!
這是地球上送子鳥們最廣泛的習俗   那里的鳥兒們...
The biggest stork convention on the planet Earth, where birds and...
朱尼爾？  干嘛？
- Uh, Junior? - What?
你在干嗎啊  我們還要去救那個寶寶啊
What are you doing? We have to save the baby.
我可是大會的超級粉絲啊
I'm just a huge fan of Storkcon.
因為這真的是太酷了
'Cause it's so cool.
那里 看！
There. Look, look, look!
他們往樓頂去了
They're headed towards the flight deck.
別大驚小怪 這能讓我冷靜
What? It calms me.
改變世界的第一個球就是
Presenting the world's first round box
我們公司的商標
Sphericus!
圓圈能圈住你的夢想
Circles can hold dreams!
我們要怎么從擁擠的人潮中穿過去
How are we gonna get through this crowd?
你們好
Hello.
我充滿著夢想
I'm full of dreams!
你們不應該回到這里的
Hey, you guys aren't supposed to be back here.
對不起了 讓一讓
Pardon me, big guy.
我充滿了夢想
I'm full of dreams!
聽我講 小郁
Listen to me, Tulip.
即使我們拿到了寶寶 我們也沒有辦法從這出去
Even if we get the baby, we have no way to get out of here.
這里太大了
Storkcon is huge
因為這里有來自世界各地的送子鳥
for storks come from all across the world...
朱尼爾 我們能不聊這話個大會了嗎
Junior, stop talking about Storkcon!
對不起 我錯了
All right, I'm sorry.
因為這讓人無法自拔啊
It's just really impressive. Here we go.
放開那個寶寶 讓我來
Put down that baby!
分析之后我們可以知道 銷售額一直在增長
Growth analytics suggest increased bandwidth
使我們能創建我們公司的企業文化
enabling us to silo creative core components.
我收到了你的短信
I got your text.
對不起 我們只找到一個飛行器
Sorry, but we could only find one jet pack.
好吧 給我飛行器 我要帶她離開這里
All right, give me the pack. I'm taking her.
不行 讓我來帶她離開  - 門都沒有
- What? No, I'm taking her. - No way.
你上次帶著她走的時候 你弄丟了她
When you had her last, you lost her.
那是因為你離開了我   - 因你炒了我
- After you left us.  - After you fired me!
因為你總會壞事
'Cause you're bad at everything.
我希望我從來就不認識你
- I wish I'd never met you.
我才希望從來就不認識你呢
well, you know what? I wish I'd never met you.
只有一件事情能讓我們結束這一切
The only good thing to come out of all of this
就是我帶著她離開
is this baby, and I am taking her.
我覺得你會太喜歡這個寶寶而舍不得離開  所以我要帶她離開
This baby is far too precious and perfect for you. I'm taking her!
- 我要帶她離開   - 我要帶她離開
- I'm taking her.  - I'm taking her!
- I'm taking her!   - I'm taking her!
那是什么？
What is that?
不  我的下半球掉了
My pants fell down. Oh, no!
- 我們到底要走哪邊   - 不知道啊
- Where are we going?  - I don't know!
好吧 不是這邊
Oh, okay. Not that way.
也不是這邊
Not that way either.
你們好啊
Hey, guys.
我們被包圍了
This is very overwhelming.
把那個東西搶走
Hand over that thing!
你們只要再靠近一步
Come one step closer,
我就放手
and I will drop this.
朱尼爾 把寶寶給我 然后我們之間就一筆勾銷
Junior, look, hand over the baby, and we'll let bygones be bygones.
甚至...
More than that.
你仍然可以成為
You can still be...
為什么這不管用了
Why isn't it working?
怎么可能只有一個寶寶
One baby?
要不再來一百萬個？
How about a million!
別！
Wait, no!
危險
Danger. Danger.
我以前想都不干想
I did not think that through.
不
No!
快關掉
- Turn it off! Turn it off!
不馬上給我停下來
You stop it this instant!
關掉這個！
Shut it down! Shut it down!
我來幫你了
This is my moment!
不
Oh, no!
- 我們上！   - 快！
- Let's go!  - Come on!
快抓住他們
Go, go, go! Grab it!
- 這里 給我就好   - 抓住
- Over here. I got this one.  - Catch it!
抓到了
Got it! Whoo!
別擋道
Out of my way! Out of my way!
不
Oh, no!
一百萬個萌寶
One million babies!
你們好 又見面了
Oh, hi.
- 不  - 不
- Oh, no!   - No!
狂歡吧
Come on!
現在就讓我結束早該結束的吧
Now it's time to do what I should've done so long ago.
摧毀萌寶工廠
Destroy the Baby Factory!
不 你不可以
No, you can't.
- 不  我可以   - 不  你不可以
- Yes, I can.   - No, you can't!
我們或許可以這樣對峙一天  但是我拒絕
We could go on like this all day. I'm just gonna go on
我現在就要摧毀萌寶工廠
and destroy the Baby Factory.
再見了 萌寶機器
Goodbye, baby-making machine.
什么鬼？
What the heck?
我早就告訴你寶寶是很聰明的
Told you babies were smart.
寶寶是很蠢的 超級蠢
Babies are dumb. Babies are super-duper dumb.
- 不 不 不 -  不 等等
- No, no, no. - No, no. Wait, no.
- 小石頭 把這給我   - 你快停下來！
- Diamond, give it back! - You stop it, this instant! Stop! Stop!
快
Come on!
什么鬼？
What?
不！
No!
你們現在別來煩我 快滾開
Now get over here and get me out of here.
好吧 你還是不要動比較好
All right. Don't move.
什么鬼？
What?
不
Oh, no.
不~~~
No!
用生命遞送！
Always deliver!
你做到了
Whoo! You did it!
我聽到我骨頭的聲音
I can hear my bones.
好了 我們應該降落了 因為我真的很痛
Yeah, we should land because this hurts so much.
我們做到了  就像我們是一家人一樣
We did it! We did it! We're a family!
是啊  我們是一...
Yes! We're a...
對不起 我好像毀了這個時刻
Sorry, I kinda ruined the moment there.
我只是有點內出血
I just have so much internal bleeding.
我們是一家人
We're a family!
看看這些
Look at that.
什么？  都我以為已經斷了
Uh, what? What? I thought it was broken.
我覺得剛剛只是脫臼了
I guess it was just dislocated.
我們剛剛落地那一刻 我可能把它接回去了
It must've popped back in when we landed.
我竟無言以對
Oh, yep. What a twist.
不
Oh, no.
好多萌寶啊
So many of them.
他們在扯我的羽毛
They're pulling my feathers!
我們應該怎么辦
What are we going to do?
所有人 聽我講一講
All right, everybody. Gather around. Gather around.
有個煩人精問過我 為什么我想做一個老板
An annoying person asked me once why I wanna be boss.
以之前一直不知道為什么
Well, I never knew why until today.
我們送子鳥的名字因為遞送萌寶而得名
Baby delivery is our true calling.
這不是只是一堆金屬和玻璃
This is not just a bunch of metal and glass
或者是任何巨大的魔力水晶制造出來的
and whatever that giant magical crystal-looking thing is made of.
這正是為什么我們送子鳥在地球上的原因
This is the heart of what storks were put on this Earth to do.
這是我們的使命
This is our mission.
我們因服務人們而自豪
We pride ourselves on customer service.
這是一個從未得到過孩子的家庭告訴我的
Well, this is a family that never got the baby they asked for.
制定一個計劃
Make a plan.
堅持實行所制定的計劃
Stick to the plan.
用生命遞送
Always deliver.
說的是不錯 但是我們沒有多余的盒子了
That's great. This is great. But we don't have any pods.
等等 大家都別慌 你們能等等嗎
Wait! Everyone, stop. Would you stop?
我有一個注意
Hey!
- 這個怎么樣   -  可以
- What about these? - Yes!
謝謝你 賈斯柏
Thank you, Jasper!
我同意
I agree.
萌寶遞送是我們送出生就開始做的事情
Baby delivery is what we're born to do.
我們應該怎么對他
Should we do anything about him?
這...
It's...
這沒關系
It's fine.
他們來了 我的天啊
They're here! Oh, my gosh.
我簡直不敢相信 他們就在我的面前
I can't believe it! They're here!
真的是他們
They're here!
在這里簽名
Sign here.
還有這里
And sign here.
這里
Initial here.
最后是這里
Initial here, here, and...
我愛你 我的女士
I love you, my little lady.
而我們會一直愛你下去
And we always will.
再見
Bye.
看來你們是送到門口的
Oh, so you deliver to the front door.
所以我們根本就沒有必要拆掉我們的房子
So we didn't have to destroy our entire house.
是啊
Yeah.
嘿 我要的是男孩兒
Yo, Stork! I ordered a brother!
男孩啊
I ordered a brother!
你想要親自喂她奶嗎
You wanna feed her her bottle?
忍者的技能！
Ninja skills.
你還好嗎
You okay?
當然 我什么事都沒有
Of course. I'm fine.
這的確很不好受
Oh, this does not feel good.
每次遞送都會想這樣嗎？
Is every delivery gonna be like this?
所以我說啊 這是一件苦差事
What can I say? It's a terrible business.
我一直一來都感到不開心
I feel so sad all the time.
不 事實上我現在很好
No. I'm actually fine now.
是啊 你看起來裝的的確很像啊
Yeah, it looks like you're handling stuff real well.
是啊 我真的沒事
Yeah. Look good, feel good.
是啊 你真棒
Yeah, pretty cool, man.
我只是在享受著美好的時刻
Just enjoying it.
你知道的 你可以對我 傾訴任何事
You know, I'm here if you wanna talk about anything.
- 我正在這里聽你講  - 不 我沒有想說的
- I'm here to listen. - Nope.
好吧  你是真的裝的很像啊
Okay, well, it seems like you're handling it pretty well.
是啊  我的確
Yeah, I am.
- 你在發抖   - 你才在發抖！
- You're shaking.  - You're shaking!
朱尼爾  你要只要把你的感想釋放出來就好了
Junior, it's okay to let your feelings out.
我沒有任何感想
I'm not feeling.
- 說出來對你比較好  - 我沒有任何感想
- It's healthy.  - I have no feelings!
相信我 說出來會好很多
Come on, let it out.
小郁
Hey.
我們都在你后面支持你
We're all right behind you.
去吧
Go on.
誰啊 親愛的？
Who is it, honey?
這是誰？ 爸爸
Who is it, Dad?
媽媽和爸爸？
Mom and Dad?
看來這就是她的家了
All right, guys.
我們已經送她到家了
We delivered her.
我們走吧
Let's go.
朱尼爾
Junior!
你要去哪里  快過來
Where are you going? Get over here.
是啊
Yeah!
- 過來啊  - 不 不 不
- Come on!  - No, no, no.
你一直口嫌體正直
You love it.
華納兄弟娛樂公司
華納兄弟動畫公司
歌曲名稱：Hold'in Out
逗鳥外傳：萌寶滿天飛
編劇&導演
尼可拉斯·史托勒
導演
道格·史威藍德
監制
布萊德·路易士
尼可拉斯·史托勒
現在喜歡我了么？
歌曲名稱：And She Was
歌曲名稱：Fire and the Flood
歌曲名稱：Kiss The Sky
修改配送地址？
你確定嗎？
是/否
地址已改
字幕糾錯請發郵件到
ljd69154@liangjundi.cn
翻譯  杰士邦
翻譯  0-8-4
校對  0-8-4
后期 &總監  0-8-4
本字幕由legendWolf原創譯制